Guide to the UE Organizers Records, 1937-2003 UE.7.3
ULS Archives & Special Collections
UE Organizers Records
1937-2003
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America
UE.7.3
64.17 Linear Feet (52 boxes)
The United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America (UE) formed in 1936 and was one of the first labor unions to affiliate with the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO). The UE hires men and women with union organizing experience to form new locals across the United States. They also inform, update, and advise existing locals on UE policy. This collection contains applications completed by those who wanted to become union organizers for the UE, as well as reports and correspondence regarding their organizing efforts.
History
The United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America (UE) formed in 1936 and was one of the first labor unions to affiliate with the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO). Between 1937 and 1962, James J. Matles, the national Director of Organization, hired men and women with union organizing experience to form new locals across the United States and Canada with the charge to increase union membership. Organizers also made locals aware of UE policies so that they would become productive members of the union. During this time, the UE sought to establish itself as an influential labor union by fighting for the rights of workers in plants owned by Westinghouse, General Electric, Philco, and others. Membership numbers reached a half million workers by the end of World War II when new legislation led to many locals being replaced by other unions whose leaders signed non-communist agreements. In 1949 the UE resigned its affiliation with the CIO and, in response, the CIO formed the competing International Union of Electrical Workers (IUE). The two unions battled into the 1950s before eventually cooperating in negotiations after a disastrous strike led by the IUE in 1960. As the McCarthy era came to a close, the UE's membership began to flourish again.
The UE's Organizing Department is divided into three levels. Stationed in the union's headquarters, the Director of Organization coordinates the activities of the International Representatives and Field Organizers. The International Representatives and Field Organizers are assigned to different geographical districts throughout the United States and Canada. While the International Representatives work on company-wide campaigns and in large geographical areas, the Field Organizers mobilize individual shops. Organizer duties include keeping current with company policies and facilities, worker habits, wages, worker issues, and key people, so that the organizer is able to enlist new members into the union. Organizers frequently design leaflets and distribute UE literature to arouse worker interest. In addition to enrolling new members, organizers are responsible for making shop workers knowledgeable of UE policies and enabling them to assume leadership at the local level. In order to keep the national office informed of all developments in organizing campaigns, organizers complete regular status reports.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains a variety of information regarding the UE's organizing efforts and provides background on the organizers who worked for the union. Included are applications completed by prospective organizers, as well as reports and correspondence which detail organizing activities at specific plants and companies.
Arrangement
Most of the files are arranged alphabetically by the organizer's last name.
This subgroup has been divided into two series as follows:
Series 7.3.1. Organizer Records
Series 7.3.2. Organizer Applications
Access Restrictions
The records of the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America are closed for a period of twenty-five years after their creation.
Acquisition Informaiton
Gift of the National Office of the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America on 1986, 1994, 1996, 2001, 2002, and 2003.
Previous Citation
UE Organizers Records, 1937-2003, UE.7.3, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
Additional collections at the Archives Service Center relating to UE organizers:
UE Campaign Materials, 1942-1990, UE.7.1, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
UE International Representatives, 1941-1972, UE.7.2, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Federal Bureau of Investigation on the UE Records, 1940-1985, UE.9.5, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
UE Organizer's Bulletins, 1937-1977, UE.7.4, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Job applications; Correspondence; Labor unions -- United States -- Officials and employees; Labor unions -- Organizing -- United States; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Electric industry workers -- Labor unions -- United States -- History; Labor; Sentner, William; Matles, James J.; Stasik, Margaret Darin; Young, Ruth; Barry, Walter; Davis, David; DeMaio, Ernest; Emspak, Julius; Gruber, Samuel; Markland, Lemuel; Quinn, Thomas J.; Riskin, Benjamin; Rivers, Charles
- Organizer Records, 7-3-1.
  Scope and Contents note
  These records contain organizer reports and correspondence regarding individual organizer's contributions to the UE. The organizers reports contain brief but complete accounts of special organizing problems, as well as comments on the status of organizing campaigns. In addition, the organizing reports include company information, such as the total amount of workers employed, the type of products manufactured, and the presence of any other unions. Organizer correspondence occurs between the organizer and the national office or other union officials, such as International Representatives or district/local officers. In most instances, the correspondence files supplement or take the place of organizer reports. In addition, the correspondence includes items such as staff applications, accounts of expenses, and other union-related business. Files from the late 1940s frequently contain a photograph of the organizer.
  - Abbe, Jeff, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbondi, Peter, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abraham, Isaac, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Acer, Richard, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adams, Paul, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Adler, Lawrence: Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adler, Lawrence: Organizer Reports, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Adour, Ann, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Africh, Rudolph, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Agler, Donald: Correspondence, 1972-1977, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Agler, Donald: Organizer Reports, 1972-1976, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Alberts, Edith, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Albright, Cory, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alfone, Joseph, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Allen, Frank, 1945-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Allen, Ruth, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Allen, Ken: Correspondence, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Allen, Ken: Organizer Reports, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Allison, Henry, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Alviene, Steven, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Amato, Michael, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Andaya, Leticia: Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Andaya, Leticia: Organizer Reports, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Anderson, Charles: Correspondence, 1946-1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Anderson, Charles: Organizer Reports, 1960-1976 (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
  - Anderson, Michael, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Annaccone, James, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Armstrong, Blanche, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Armstrong, Honore, 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Arnado, Glen: Correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Arnado, Glen: Organizer Reports, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Asher, Emil, 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Aslin, Mildred, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Austin, Leland: Organizer Reports, 1966-75 (Box 1, Folder 37-38)
  - Authelet, Harry, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Avellar, Walter, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Axt, Louis, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Bacon, David, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baer, Theodore, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bahow, Karen: Correspondence, 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bahow, Karen: Organizer Reports, 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 04-05)
  - Bahssin, Lucille, 1944-1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Baldasseroni, Ronald: Correspondence, 1963-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Baldasseroni, Ronald: Organizer Reports, 1964-1982 (Box 2, Folder 08-10)
  - Banks, Frank Jr., 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Baptist, Joan: Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Baptist, Joan: Organizer Reports, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Barile, Pat, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Barnes, Walter, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Barnett, Muriel, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Barros, Manuel, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Barry, Walter, 1938-1950 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Barry, William: Correspondence, 1974-1983 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
  - Barry, William: Organizer Reports, 1974-1983 (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - Bastian, Ann, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Batke, Henry, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Beal, Edwin, 1938-1942 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Benitez, Nelson: Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Benitez, Nelson: Organizer Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Bennett, David, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Benson, Harold, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Bentley, William, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Berger, Sadelle, 1944-1948 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Bergman, Rudy, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Bernard, John, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Bernstein, Daniel, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Bersing, Carl, 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Besch, Peter, 1937-1962 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Best, Reginal, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Betts, Stan, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Bianco, Darrio, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Biegner, Joseph: Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Biegner, Joseph: Organizer Reports, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Bigman, Paul: Correspondence, 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bigman, Paul: Organizer Reports, 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 02-03)
  - Bingaman, Clarence, 1943-1946 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Birchfield, Robert, 1968-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bishop, Alfred, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bishop, Phillip, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bittman, John, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bizsky, John, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Black, Thelma, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bliss, Willard, 1940-1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bloch, Edward: Personal Correspondence, 1949-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bloch, Edward: Correspondence, 1954-1990 (Box 3, Folder 13-16)
  - Bloch, Edward: Organizer Reports, 1954-1984 (Box 3, Folder 17-20)
  - Block, Bernice, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Block, Boris: Correspondence, 1950-1973 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
  - Block, Boris: Organizer Reports, 1951-1972 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
  - Bloom, Frank, 1940-1943 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Boardman, Christine: Correspondence, 1981-1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Boardman, Christine: Organizer Reports, 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Boggs, John, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Bollen, Donald: Correspondence, 1942-1951, 1971-1984 (Box 4, Folder 01-04)
  - Bollen, Donald: Organizer Reports, 1973-1985 (Box 4, Folder 05-07)
  - Bond, Mercedes, 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bordis, Harry: Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bordis, Harry: Organizer Reports, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Born, Kenneth, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bornholtz, Robert, 1947-1952 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Boyd, Eugene, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Boyd, John, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Boylan, Paul, 1939-1941 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bracamonte, Lydia: Correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Bracamonte, Lydia: Organizer Reports, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Bramlett, Lonnie Jr., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Brandon, Louise: Correspondence, 1985-1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Brandon, Louise: Organizer Reports, 1986-1993 (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
  - Brandon, Peter: Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 22-24)
  - Brandon, Peter: Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Brandon, Peter: Organizer Reports, 1974-1978 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Brant, Carl, 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Brant, Carl, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brashear, Dewey, 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Braswell, Richard: Correspondence, 1978-1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Braswell, Richard: Organizer Reports, 1978-1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Breiner, George, 1940-1943 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Briney, Harold, 1957-1962 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Brito, Mario, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Brito, Mario, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Brown, Charles, 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Brown, Dolores, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Brown, Fred: Correspondence, 1981-1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Brown, Fred: organizer Reports, 1981-1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Brown, Robert, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Bruno, Edmond: Correspondence, 1973-2000 (Box 5, Folder 15-19)
  - Bruno, Edmond: Organizer Reports, 1973-1986 (Box 5, Folder 20-23)
  - Brunswick, James, 1951-1953 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Brzostowski, Guillermo: Correspondence, 1976-1987 (Box 6, Folder 01-02)
  - Brzostowski, Guillermo: Organizer Reports, 1976-1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Buchholtz, Kent: Correspondence, 1987-1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Buchholtz, Kent: Organizer Reports, 1987-1991 (Box 6, Folder 05-06)
  - Buczek, Ted: Correspondence, 1941-1976 (Box 6, Folder 07-08)
  - Buczek, Ted: Organizer Reports, 1949-1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Budd, Larry, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Burch, William, 1950-1958 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Burdick, Alan, 1943-1947 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Burger, Chad, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Burman, Irving, 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Burns, Frank, 1943-1951 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Burns, Milt, 1951-1955 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Burton, Renee, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Buse, Robert, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Busky, Estelle, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Cadwell, Leo, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Cahn, William B., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Caiazza, Joseph, 1940-1947 (Box 6, Folder 22-24)
  - Callahan, William, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Callicoat, June, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Caltabiano, Hank, 1984-1994 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Camacho, Humberto: Correspondence, 1962-1997 (Box 6, Folder 28-30)
  - Camacho, Humberto: Organizer Reports, 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Camacho, Humberto: Organizer Reports, 1968-1997 (Box 7, Folder 01-05)
  - Canales, Marcial, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cannon, Charles, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Caputo, Jean, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Carbone, Edward: Correspondence, 1962-1993 (Box 7, Folder 09-11)
  - Carbone, Edward: Organizer Reports, 1965-1992 (Box 7, Folder 12-15)
  - Carboneau, Marc, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Carlin, Shane: Correspondence, 1990-1999 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Carlin, Shane: Organizer Reports, 1991-1999 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Carlson, Reuben, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Carpenter, Ethel, 1947-1954 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Carter, Earl, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Carter, Zack: Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Carter, Zack: Organizer Reports, 1989-1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Carver, Ilene: Correspondence, 1982-1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Carver, Ilene: Organizer Reports, 1982-1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Carver, Ronald: Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Carver, Ronald: Miscellaneous, 1976-1988 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Carver, Ronald: Organizer Reports, 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Casamo, William, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Case, John: Correspondence, 1976-1991 (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - Case, John: Organizer Reports, 1973-1985, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
  - Cassidy, Martin, 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 15-18)
  - Castillo, Jose, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Cerda, Raymond, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Cerulli, Joseph, 1942-1944 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Cesarotti, Maurice, 1941-1943 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Cetina, Miguel, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Cetner, Joseph, 1940-1943 (Box 8, Folder 24-25)
  - Chakreotes, James, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Chambers, William, 1940-1941 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Chandler, Henrietta, 1944-1953 (Box 8, Folder 28-29)
  - Chandrl, Margaret, 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Chaplan, Patrick: Organizer Reports, 1960-1969 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Chaplan, Patrick: Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 8, Folder 32-33)
  - Chaplan, Patrick: Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 9, Folder 01-02)
  - Chase, Dorothy, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Chernow, Etta, 1943-1945 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Cherry, Granville, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Chessin, Henry, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Choder, Leona, 1944-1946 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Chown, Paul: Correspondence, 1944-1976 (Box 9, Folder 08-11)
  - Chown, Paul: Organizer Reports, 1964-1975 (Box 9, Folder 12-13)
  - Chicollo, Frank, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Chyrywaty, Joseph, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Cierny, George, 1945-1948 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Cilli, Nicholas, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Cioffari, Albert, 1953-1973 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Clancey, Regina, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Clark, Paul, 1952-1956 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Clark, Robert, 2001-2003 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Clark, William, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Clarke, Rose, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Claset, Glowell, 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Cline, Linda, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Clinton, Rose, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Clough, Almond, 1941-1945 (Box 9, Folder 27-28)
  - Clouser, George, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Cluka, Earl, 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Clune, Michael, 1950-1952 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Clutz, Richard, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Cmero, Frank, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Coburn, Charles, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Cohen, David, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Cohen, Hy, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Cohen, Sylvia, 1945-1947 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Cole, Archer, 1945-1947 (Box 9, Folder 38-39)
  - Collins, William, 1979-1984 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Colonizers Applications, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Colter, Virginia, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Colvin, Dennis, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Colwell, Gordon, 1943-1947 (Box 9, Folder 44-45)
  - Coman, Kathy, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Compa, Lance: Correspondence, 1973-1989 (Box 10, Folder 01-02)
  - Compa, Lance: Organizer Reports, 1973-1977 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Compa, Lance: Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Compton, Robert, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Connelly, Francis, 1948-1953 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Conroy, James, 1941-1946 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Conroy, William, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Cook, Archie, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Cook, James, 1999-2003 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Cook, Shawn, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Cornell, Dru, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Cortor, William, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Corra, Joseph, 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Costa, Michael, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Costello, Cristy: Correspondence, 1992-1999 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Costello, Cristy: Organizer Reports, 1992-1998 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Cotton, John: Correspondence, 1972-1982 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Cotton, John: Organizer Reports, 1976-1982 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Cover, Lawrence, 1944-1946 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Covington, William: Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Covington, William: Organizer Reports, 1989-1993 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Coyle, Grace, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Crawford, Elmer, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Creegan, Barney, 1938-1939 (Box 10, Folder 25-26)
  - Creekmore, Sheridan, 1952-1956 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Criley, Florence: Correspondence, 1945-1976 (Box 10, Folder 28-31)
  - Criley, Florence: Organizer Reports, 1960-1976 (Box 10, Folder 32-33)
  - Criscuolo, Walton, 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Crook, Mary-Erin, 1986-1995 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Crowell, Robin, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Curry, Kathleen: Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Curry, Kathleen: Organizer Reports, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Curtin, Timothy, 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - D'Amelia, Vincent, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - DaCosta, Fernando: Organizer Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Daduk, Stephen, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Daggett, Emerson, 1942-1945 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Dale, Lawrence, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Danforth, Marian, 1942-1947 (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
  - Darin, Margaret, 1942-1944 (Box 11, Folder 14-17)
  - Daub, James, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Daughtery, James: Correspondence, 1962-1970 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Daughtery, James: Organizer Reports, 1962-1970 (Box 11, Folder 20-22)
  - Davidson, John, 1972-1978 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Davidson, Margaret, 1946-1947 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Davis, David, 1953-1957 (Box 11, Folder 25-26)
  - Davis, Ester (Terry): Correspondence, 1979-2000 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Davis, Ester (Terry): Organizer Reports, 1980-2000 (Box 11, Folder 28-30)
  - Davis, Jack, 1941-1950 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Davis, Raymond, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Davis, Robert, 1938-1943 (Box 11, Folder 33-35)
  - Davis, Sam, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Davis, Susannah: Correspondence, 1992-1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Davis, Susannah: Organizer Reports, 1992-1997 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Dawson, Lawrence, 1945-1946 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Day, Larry, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 04-05)
  - Dean, Emil, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Deane, Elaine, 1952-1955 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Deane, Leone, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 08-09)
  - Dear, George, 1942-1945 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Decker, Derek, 1946-1947 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Dee, Ann, 1951-1952 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Dee, Winchard, 1948-1950 (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
  - DeJonghe, William, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Delaney, Thomas, 1943-1957 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Del Pozzo, Theresa, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - DeMaio, Anthony: Correspondence, 1939-1970 (Box 12, Folder 18-23)
  - DeMaio, Anthony: Organizer Reports, 1949-1967 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - DeMaio, Daniel, 1984-1987 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - DeMaio, Ernest, 1936-1953 (Box 12, Folder 26-40)
  - DeMaio, Ernest, 1936-1953 (Box 13, Folder 01-12)
  - DeMoura, Antone, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Demps, Robert, 1952-1953 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Dempskie, Joseph, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Dermody, Joseph, 1952-1972 (Box 13, Folder 16-18)
  - Derrickson, Gene, 1948-1953 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Deso, Robert, 1945-1946 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - DeVore, James: Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - DeVore, James: Organizer Reports, 1966-1971 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Dewald, Everett, 1946-1947 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Diamond, Abe, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Diener, Lucille, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - DiPatre, Frank, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - DiPinto, Antonio, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Dixon, Robert, 1942-1943 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Dizard, Charles: Correspondence, 1970-1978 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Dizard, Charles: Organizer Reports, 1975-1978 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Dluggoff, Arthur, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Dodson, George, 1941-1948 (Box 13, Folder 32-33)
  - Donldson, Ruth, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Donnelly, James, 1944-1947 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Donovan, Mary, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Dougherty, Lyle, 1942-1943 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Dove, Curtis, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Dowling, Arnold, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Dowling, Lyle, 1941-1944 (Box 13, Folder 40-41)
  - Draham, Annemarie: Correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Draham, Annemarie: Organizer Reports, 1989-1995 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Driscoll, Michael, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Ducey, John, 1952-1953 (Box 13, Folder 45)